[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Kyle：什么是承诺？
&gt;&gt; Kyle: What is a promise?
有很多不同的方式，
There are a multitude of different ways,
承诺有几种不同的解释方式，我将选择两种或两种
several different ways that promises are explained and I will choose two or
这里通过比喻和例证的方式解释了其中的三个。
three of those explanations here by way of metaphor and illustration.
再说一次，因为对我来说更重要的是你理解这个概念
Again, because it's more important to me that you understand the concept
先承诺后，再理解API。
behind promises first, before understanding the API.
这与大多数这类东西通常被教授的方式相反。
It's the reverse of the way most of this stuff is typically taught.
但我想让你明白为什么承诺如此重要。
But I want you to understand why promises are so important.
因为他们并不完美。
Because they're not perfect.
当你对这个承诺感到沮丧，或者是一些奇怪的事情时，
And when there is some frustration with the promise, or something that's weird,
或者有一些问题，那里有问题。
or there's some gotcha, there are gotchas there.
当你在路上遇到一些麻烦，你很沮丧
And when there's some gotcha down the road and you're frustrated and
你找到了你自己。
you find yourself.
这里有个线索。
Here's a clue.
有一种东西叫做诺言地狱。
There's is such a thing as promises hell.
如果有回电卖出，就有卖出的承诺。
If there's a call back sell, there's a promise to sell.
当你发现自己陷入承诺地狱时，你会诅咒他们。
When you find yourself stuck in promises hell in your cursing at them.
我不想让你转身说，好吧，我只是摆脱问题。
I don't want you to turn around and say, well I just get rid of problems.
需要理解为什么它们更重要
Need to understand why they're more important,
而不仅仅是他们的API的使用。
than just the usage of their API.
如果我可以改变它，我会改变API的一些东西。
If I could change it, there are some things I would change about the API.
但我不会改变他们在那里的事实。
But I wouldn't change the fact that they're there.
它们是我们所取得的最重要的进步之一
They are one of the most important advances that we've made in
编码合理的异步编码模式。
codifying reasonable asynchronous coding patterns.
所以，首先让我给你一个关于承诺的场景。
So, first let me give you a scenario around promises.
这很愚蠢，在这里很早就在一起
It's silly, where it's early here together and
我想确保我们都醒了
I want to make sure that we're all kind of awake.
我看到人们喝着咖啡，所以喝了更多的咖啡，
I see people sipping on coffee and so have more coffee,
因为你的大脑今天必须开动所有的气缸才能拿到东西。
cuz your brains are gonna have to fire on all cylinders to get stuff today.
但这里有个愚蠢的比喻要解释给你听。
But here's a silly metaphor to explain to you.
我走到我最喜欢的快餐店的柜台前，然后
I walk up to the counter at my favorite fast food restaurant, and
我点了一个芝士汉堡。
I order a cheeseburger.
所以我问这位女士，我想要一个芝士汉堡，她说，
So I asked the lady, I'd like a cheeseburger and she says,
一共是39美元。
that will be a $39.
所以我把钱递给她，给她39美元。
And so I hand her the money, give her the $39.
所以我已经通过订购和
So I have begun the transaction by ordering and
为某事付出一些钱。
giving some money for something.
我期望这笔交易的回报是什么？
What am I expecting in return of this transaction?
我在等芝士汉堡。
I'm expecting a cheeseburger.
但通常情况下，我不会马上拿到芝士汉堡。
But oftentimes, I'm not handed a cheeseburger immediately.
我被给予了什么？
What instead am I given?
一张收据，重要的是收据上有订单号，对吧？
A receipt, and importantly on that receipt it has an order number on it, right?
我的订单上写着，317号订单。
My order says, order number 317.
所以我拿着收据，看着我的订单号，然后
So I take that receipt, and I look at my order number, and
这个订单号已经成为我未来芝士汉堡的一个占位符。
that order number has become a placeholder for my future cheeseburger.
这是一张借条。
It is an IOU.
这是对未来芝士汉堡的承诺。
It is a promise for a future cheeseburger.
他们欠我一个芝士汉堡因为我给了钱，
They owe me a cheeseburger because I have given the money,
我已经开始交易了。
I've started a transaction.
现在，我还没有奶酪汉堡，我不能咬它，但是
Now, I don't have the cheeseburger yet, I can't bite into it, but
这并不意味着我不能开始思考
that doesn't mean I can't begin to think about and
思考和梦想我未来的芝士汉堡。
reason about and dream about my future cheeseburger.
我可以开始思考它在我的嘴里可以开始流口水，我可以在和
I can begin to think about it in my mouth can begin to salivate and I can be in and
让芝士汉堡在我的脑海里翩翩起舞
have cheeseburgers dancing in my head about how
令人惊讶的是这个芝士汉堡会是，我饿死了，我迫不及待地想吃了。
amazing this cheeseburger is gonna be, I'm famished, I can't wait to eat it.
我手里有东西可以让我开始
I have something in my hand that allows me to begin to
关于这个芝士汉堡的原因，即使我还没有它。
reason about this cheeseburger, even though I don't yet have it.
然后那些神奇的话，命令317。
And then those magical words, order 317.
我走回柜台，手里拿着收据，上面印着317号订单。
And I walk back up to the counter, receipt in hand, order 317 printed on it.
我把收据递给她，现在我得到了什么回报？
And I hand her my receipt, and what do I now get in return?
我现在正在用这个承诺来换取价值本身。
I now am exchanging that promise for the value for the value itself.
这是一个愚蠢的比喻，但仍然是一个比喻
This is a silly metaphor, but a metaphor nonetheless for
承诺发生了什么。
what is happening with promises.
承诺是一个量化的想法，我们需要一个地方
Promises are a quantification of the idea that we need a place
持有者消除时间是围绕价值的关注。
holder to eliminate time is the concern wrapped around the value.
我们需要一个容器围着它。
We need a container around it.
在编程语言中，我们称其为未来值。
In programming speak, we call that a future value.
这是一个最终会在某个未指明的点上实现的价值。
It's a value that will eventually at some unspecified point become fulfilled.
但与此同时
But in the meantime,
我们仍然需要能够以完全相同的方式对其进行推理。
we still need to be able to reason about it exactly the same way.
因为我们不想坐在那里等待和疑惑
Because we don't want to sit around waiting and wondering and
拥有所有这些不同逻辑的叉子。
having all these forks of different logic.
这就是使我们的代码变得复杂的原因。
That's the complexity that makes our code.
很难理解，很难维护，很难没有虫子。
Hard to understand, hard to maintain, hard to be bug free.
因此，承诺变成了一个包装在值周围的容器。
So the promise becomes a container that wraps around a value.
如果我们的承诺主要是通过
If that promises come to us primarily by way and
它们不是JavaScript的原创。
they're not original to JavaScript.
但它们主要是通过一种叫做E的语言来到我们身边的。
But they come to us primarily by way of a language called E.
TC39委员会的成员之一，马克·米勒。
One of the members of the TC 39 Committee, Mark Miller.
是E编程语言的创造者，在E中他们有这些东西
Is the creator of the E programming language, and in E they have these things
叫做期货，在E中，未来被它的价值所取代，
called futures, and in E a future is literally replaced by it's value,
从字面上看，它是按其值进行交换的，但您可以执行操作
it's literally exchanged by its value but you can perform the operations
您通常会直接、透明地对该值执行的操作。
that you would normally do against that value directly, transparently.
即使这个值还没有实际存在，你也可以开始编写它，
Even though the value isn't physically there yet, you can begin to compose it,
您可以开始对执行操作。
you can begin to perform operations on.
我们可以得到完全相同的东西，但他说你知道吗，
We can get quite the same thing but he said you know what,
这真的很强大，我们应该给JavaScript带来一些东西
this is really powerful and we should bring something to JavaScript that
允许人们对它的价值进行推理而忽略了时机。
allows people to reason about values it ignorance of the timing.
价值观是重要的东西，构成价值观是重要的事情。
Values are the important thing and composing values is the important thing.
如果听起来像是与函数式编程有关，那是因为它是。
If it sounds like it's kind of related to functional programming, that's cuz it is.
不是在这些术语中反省，而是承诺，不是他们的API，而是
Not to throwback in those terms but promises, not their API but
他们的机制，他们基本上是一个单子。
their mechanism, they're basically a monad.
它们是函数式编程概念。
They're a functional programming concept.
API并不像函数式程序员所希望的那样干净
The API is not quite as clean as a functional programmer would like and
已经有实验来创建更多的其他版本
there have been experiments to create other versions that are more
功能健全，但原理仍然相同。
functionally sound, but the principle still the same.
所以如果它听起来很实用，那是因为它就是这样。
So if it sounds functional, it's because it is.
所以，这是对承诺的一种思考方式，就是它是一种未来价值。
So that's one way of thinking about a promise is that it's a future value.
另一种思考承诺的方式是
Another way of thinking about a promise is that it
A颠倒了我们传统上使用的范式
an uninverts the paradigm that we're traditionally used
与其他一些本质上是异步的机制进行交互。
to interacting with some other mechanism that's going to be asynchronous in nature.
当我调用某个实用程序并且我知道该实用程序现在不会完成时，
When I call some utility and I know that utility's not going to finish now,
它将在晚些时候结束。
it's going to finish at some later point.
当我称之为公用事业的时候。
When I call that utility.
我怎么能等着听呢？
How do I wait around to hear that?
我得给它回个电话。
I have to give it a call back.
我得给你回个电话你还记得我说过
I have to pass a call back in and you remember I said,
这是控制的反转。
that's inversion of control.
当我在回调中结束我的程序的后半部分时
When I wrap up the second half of my program in a callback and
把它传给别人，我给他们延续控制权。
pass it to someone else, I give them the continuation control.
我已经颠倒了我所拥有的控制力。
And I've inverted the control that I have.
但是如果我们可以颠倒这个范式呢？
But what if we could un-invert that paradigm?
如果我们可以，不倒相器而不是倒相器在第一位？
If we could, un-inverter rather not inverted in the first place?
而不是将调用传递回实用程序，
Rather than passing a call back to a utility,
如果我们可以这样说，我要调用一些函数
what if we could say something like, I'm gonna call some function and
我知道它可能需要一段时间才能完成。
I know it might take a while for it to finish.
我要你回到我身边
I want you to return to me,
当我打电话给公用事业公司的时候，我想让你给我一些东西。
when I call utility, I want you to give me back something.
我要你给我一个事件监听器。
I want you to give me an event listener.
我可以订阅完成事件的事件侦听器。
An event listener that I can subscribe to a completion event.
因此，我将监听事件的完成，而您只需激发该事件
So I'll listen for the completion of events and you just fire that event
只要你准备好了，我就会通过这个事件监听器得到通知
whenever you're good and ready, and I'll be notified through this event listener
你已经完成了你的工作，我知道是时候继续前进了。
that you've finished your work and I'll know it's time to move on.
事实上，除了完成这件事之外，
In fact, in addition to being a completion of that,
我还可以监听错误事件。
I can also listen to an error event.
如果你有一些差事要通知我或其他你想通知我的事情
If you had some errand to notify me or other things that you want to notify me
关于，我可以简单的接收你的听众
about, I could simply receiving that listener back from you and
我知道这是一种尝试过的真实模式来接收并倾听。
I know that's a tried and true patterns to receive something and listen to it.
收听订阅上面的事件。
Listen subscribe to events on it.